# Yeongbin Hwang

Master's Student

School of Electrical Engineering Email: hyb3565800@gmail.com

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) Homepage: https://yeongbin.dev/

# SUMMARY

I am a Master's student in the System Security Lab at KAIST, advised by Professor Yongdae Kim. My research interests are: 1) to implement the testing framework for inspecting new infrastructure like 5G and other network architectures 2) to analyze the infrastructure in 5G and other network architectures 3) to find and exploit software and hardware vulnerabilities in cellular networks. Especially, I'm putting my effort into analyzing 5G core network structure and security.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST), South Korea

M.S. in School of Electrical Engineering

Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2023

Thesis Title: Stateful Black Box Testing of 5G StandAlone Network

Advisor: Prof. Yongdae Kim

B.S. in School of Computing

Feb. 2016 - Feb. 2021

URP program: Detecting standard violations in the commercial cellular network based on state machine

extraction

Advisor: Prof. Yongdae Kim

# PROJECT

#### 5G Core Network Testing

2021 - 2022

- Implemented a framework based on Open5GCore to test the vulnerabilities of the 5G core network. The framework consists of three main components: 1) a Fuzzer that continues testing on UE pod, 2) a Controller that captures packets on the host and relays them to the target, and 3) an Analyzer that analyzes the results of the test [2].
- Analyzed the 5G core network using the framework considering various attack models [1].

#### Systematization of Knowledge in Cellular Network

2021 - 2022

Investigated vulnerabilities existing in cellular networks using symmetric keys and analyzed whether it was possible to solve the vulnerabilities when PKI was applied.

# Comparative Analysis in Various State Machines

2020 - 2021

Implemented a framework that collects the UE side logs and builds state machines of networks: conduct the study - showing that state machines of networks are different to cause some implementation flaws [5].

## MitM Environment: can verify the attack scenarios

2019 - 2020

- Designed and implemented MitM(Man in the Middle) environment in the LTE network to verify vulnerabilities found through formal analysis. This MitM simulator executes the attack scenario and determines whether the network or user functions normally for it.
- Validated each attack scenario that is found in formal analysis.

# SKILL

## Programming Language

C, C++, Python, Javascript (Node.js)

#### Framework and Tool

Kubernetes, Docker, Open source LTE and 5G software (srsRAN, open5GS), Wireshark

#### **Publications**

#### 1. Procedure Collision Testing for 5G SA Network

Yeongbin Hwang, Mincheol Son and Yongdae Kim

Conference on Mobile Internet Security (MobiSec'22)

# 2. 5GTesting: Framework for NAS Vulnerability Analysis of 5G SA Network with Stateful Testing

Yeongbin Hwang, CheolJun Park, Mincheol Son and Yongdae Kim

Conference on Information Security and Cryptography Summer (CISC-W'22)

## 3. Preventing Voice Phishing Using CMC Call Analysis and Detection

Junho Ahn, Sangwook Bae, Beomseok Oh, Yonghwa Lee, Jiho Lee, <u>Yeongbin Hwang</u>, Takkyung Oh, Mincheol Son and Yongdae Kim

Conference on Information Security and Cryptography Summer (CISC-S'22)

## 4. Revealing the limitations of operating LTE downlink sniffers in real-world

Tuan Hoang Dinh, Sangwook Bae, Cheoljun Park, Jiho Lee, Taekkyung Oh, Mincheol Son, <u>Yeongbin Hwang</u> and Yongdae Kim

Conference on Information Security and Cryptography Winter (CISC-W'21)

# 5. A Study on Fault Detection in LTE Network: A Black-Box Testing for LTE Network Components

Jiho Lee, Hongil Kim, Sangwook Bae, Mincheol Son, Cheoljun Park, Seokbin Yun,  $\underline{\textbf{Yeongbin Hwang}}$  and Yongdae Kim

Conference on Information Security and Cryptography Winter (CISC-W'20)

# 6. VolteFuzz: Framework for Comprehensive Analysis of SIP in Volte

Seokbin Yun, Sangwook Bae, Mincheol Son, Jiho Lee, Cheoljun Park,  $\underline{\textbf{Yeongbin Hwang}}$ , Yongdae Kim and Dongkwan Kim

Conference on Information Security and Cryptography Winter (CISC-W'20)

# 7. Coercive FBS Redirection Attack using Unicast Message Injection in LTE

Cheoljun Park, Sangwook Bae, Mincheol Son, Jiho Lee, Hongil Kim, Seokbin Yun,  $\underline{\textbf{Yeongbin Hwang}}$  and Yongdae Kim

Conference on Information Security and Cryptography Summer (CISC-S'20)

# AWARD

#### Academic Awards

Best Paper Award (i.e., 행정안전부 장관 최우수논문상), CISC-W

Nov. 2022

Title: 5GTesting: Framework for NAS Vulnerability Analysis of 5G SA Network with Stateful Testing Best Paper Award (i.e., 한국전자통신연구원 원장상), CISC-W Nov. 2020

Title: Coercive FBS Redirection Attack using Unicast Message Injection in LTE

## **PATENTS**

#### Applications

US20220124504A1 Apr. 2022

Method for validating man-in-the-middle attack for cellular control plane protocols and the system thereof KR20220050767A Apr. 2022

Method for validating man-in-the-middle attack for cellular control plane protocols and the system thereof

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### System Security Laboratory (KAIST), Research Intern

Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Implemented MitM(Man in the Middle) attacker in LTE network.

Professor: Yongdae Kim.

# Network and System Security Laboratory (KAIST), Research Intern

Sep. 2019 – Dec. 2019

Research on the dark web. Professor: Seungwon Shin.

# Computer Architecture and Memory Systems Laboratory (KAIST), Research Intern J

Jun.

2019 - Aug. 2019

Kernel programming for improving the speed to access the memory.

Professor: Myoungsoo Jung.

# PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

#### Secondary Reviewer (Security)

USENIX Security Symposium (Security)

IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland)

2022

ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS)

2021 – 2022

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, Programming Structure for Electrical Engineering (EE209)	Fall 2022
Teaching Assistant, Software Security (EE595)	Spring 2022
Teaching Assistant, Software development environment and tools practice (EE485)	Fall 2021
Teaching Assistant, Introduction to Programming (CS101)	Fall 2020

# LIST OF REFERENCES

## Dr. Yongdae Kim

Chair Professor, KAIST

Professor, School of Electrical Engineering and Graduate School of Information Security, KAIST

Homepage: https://syssec.kaist.ac.kr/~yongdaek/